<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>:#/ Gioele SL Fierro</title><link>http://gslf.it/</link><description>Gioele Stefano Luca Fierro</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hck@gslf.it (GioeleSLFierro)</managingEditor><webMaster>hck@gslf.it (GioeleSLFierro)</webMaster><copyright>Gioele SL Fierro 2021 ©.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 18:44:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gslf.it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[MachineLearning] How to build a spam classifier</title><link>http://gslf.it/mlnaivespamclassifier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 18:44:20 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://gslf.it/mlnaivespamclassifier/</guid><description>Detecting Spam messages is one of the first tasks assigned to Machine Learning algorithms, and Bayesian classifiers are the perfect choice for this job. Let’s see more about Machine Learning spam detection with a little bit of theory and fully functional implementation in Python.
Bayes’ theorem is a cornerstone of statistics, it correlates the conditional probability (prior probability) of an event to the probability measure (posterior probabilities) of the same event.</description></item><item><title>Starting learning Go – a journey for developers</title><link>http://gslf.it/learninggo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 18:40:49 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://gslf.it/learninggo/</guid><description>I have been a professional software developer for more than fifteen years. I’m proficient in C/C++ and Python. I know Javascript (with some framework) and Java well. The last language I learned to use (10 years ago) is Python.
After all this time, I had to test myself again with a new language to learn from scratch. I have been cultivating this idea for a long time because I have very little time available due to my working commitments with Globsit.</description></item><item><title>Hugo Startup</title><link>http://gslf.it/hugo-startup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 15:08:38 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://gslf.it/hugo-startup/</guid><description>I started to play with Hugo today!
Tired of the complexity (useless for a site like this) of Wordpress, and in love as always with VIM and the CLI, I switched to Hugo, a tool for publishing sites based on markdown plain text files. Now I can manage all site configurations and content via command line. At the moment everything is hosted on GitHub, in the main repository of my account.</description></item></channel></rss>